This is software engineering radio, the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at
se-radio.net. SE Radio is brought to you
by the ITE computer society and by it
software magazine online at
computer.org/software. This is Sam
Tagert for SE Radio. I'm here today with
Steve Summers. Steve is the security
lead for aerospace and defense systems
at NI and focuses on the security of
mechanical test systems. He has worked
in the test and measurement industry for
more than 25 years. In full disclosure,
I personally am an NI partner and Lab
View champion. And today, Steve and I
are going to talk about securing test
and measurement equipment. And before we
get started, we've talked about similar
subjects on this podcast. In episodes
such as episode 639, Cody Eerson on
regulated industries, episode 541 with
John Harband and Donald Fischer on
supply chain security, and 587 with M.
Scott Ford on managing dependency
freshness. Welcome, Steve. Thank you.
Let's start by defining test and
measurement equipment. What exactly are
we talking about securing? Great
question. When I talk to engineers, of
course, I talk about the ability to test
products that they're making. But if I'm
talking to my grandma, my grandpa, you
know, and trying to explain what we do
in tester measurement. What we do is we
help engineers test the products that
are delivered to customers, right? When
you buy a new phone, you don't want it
to come out of the box dead. If you buy
a new car, you don't want any of the
parts to not work. So, we're helping to
test all of those components and the
systems before they deliver. Really what
we are is the interface between the
physical and the virtual world, right?
Because if you're testing an airplane
wing, you need to bring those signals
into your computer somehow. And because
we're playing that interface role of
connecting from the real world to the
virtual world, that makes security kind
of interesting and also really important
because now we're actually touching
things. And in the test world that means
one thing but the fact that we play that
broader role of just interfacing to the
real world means that in some cases
we're controlling pumps and valves and
electrical circuits and electrical grids
and we're doing solar power testing and
those kinds of things. All of that is
more interesting in this new security
world because now if somebody can break
into one of our test systems or into one
of our systems that's connected to the
real world that gives them a way to go
from their malicious habitat right into
an actual physical thing which might be
a self-driving car. It might be a
picture frame as we'll talk about. It
might be all kinds of different things.
So that's what we're really trying to
get to, right? How do we secure those
things that allow us to connect to the
real world so we can do things like
perform test? So, if I understand you
correctly, what you're saying is that
the consequences can be much higher with
this type of equipment as opposed to a
computer system that's just a database
for a bank or something like that. Yeah.
If you think about some of the more
interesting stories we see on the news,
you hear about banks and schools and
hospitals being hijacked for money and
that's really bad. I'm not trying to
downplay that at all. That really
stakes. But the stories that become
really interesting is when they cut off
our gas supply, when they cut down our
electrical grid, when they interfere
with our traffic lights, when they
interfere with the products that we have
and so this world of operational
technology is how we kind of
differentiate from informationational
technology. So this world of operational
technology is a big fat target because
the consequences of it can be so much
greater than just draining your bank
account. So when you say operations
technologies is that when I hear people
refer to the word OT that's what they're
referring to. Exactly. And so you'll see
in some of the government documentation
they'll differentiate between an IT
system and an OT system and that's what
they mean as operational technology. So
if I wanted to understand that correctly
then it would be something that is
connected moreformational more databases
and transferring data back and forth
whereas OT is more interacting with the
real world. Yeah. Think about
operational technology as you can think
about as the back end of the office. So
the front end of the office, all the
websites and the finance systems, all of
that that is informationational
technology. The back end is the PLC's,
the robots, the automation, the field
things like valves and airports and all
of those pieces, those are all
operational technology. So you use the
term PLC's. Do you want to say what that
is just for those who might not know?
Yeah. So when you start getting into
automating something, right? If you're
automating a production line or if
you're automating a roller coaster, you
need some kind of a controller that can
control that world. And most often that
is done through discrete inputs and
outputs. And one very common way of
doing that is with programmable logic
controllers and those are PLC's. So
those are made by big companies like
Alen Bradley and Seammens and they're
programmed through digital logic and
those are very very common. My company
at National Instruments, we don't make
PLC's, but because we play this world of
the interface between the real world and
the virtual world, one of the
interesting things that we do is that we
make analog controllers that can control
some of those circuits. So sometimes
rather than just looking at a gate or a
door and say, is that door open? If the
door is open, then flash this light,
which is what a PLC is great for. We
look at things like how fast is
something changing? You know, is
something vibrating? Is it vibrating out
of control? If so, then go turn this
other pump on or turn it off. So, we're
controlling analog circuits by reading
analog signals. That's a lot harder for
a PLC to do. And so, that's actually
something that we do really well because
we come from the world of analog
circuitry and doing all the other kinds
of testing and the other interfacing
that we talked about. In general, what
is the threat model for these types of
OT systems? So, that's a good question,
right? So the the threat model, it
varies a little bit by application, a
lot by application, right? So we are
doing everything from testing a silicon
chip on that's going to be mass-
prodduced in millions. We're testing
some of those on semiconductor
production lines. We're testing laptops
and cell phones. We're testing medical
devices. We're testing airplanes and
airplane components. And we're
controlling valves as I was describing a
minute ago. We're we're controlling
those other broader systems. And so that
question of threat modeling is something
that every engineer has to look at and
think about specifically for their
system. But if you were to generalize
it, if you are at the end of the
production line in your testing, that's
a juicy target for a hacker or a
malicious actor to place some kind of
malicious code that he can then spread
in mass quantities out to the world. So,
a few years ago, there was an incident
where these picture frames that we' buy
and give to our grandparents for
Christmas, and you can put it on their
network, their wireless network, and
then you can update your photos to those
photo frames. So, those are cool. Like,
I've got one at my house. And when those
hit the end of the production line a few
years ago, there was a tester in the
production area in China or wherever it
was that had a virus and it was
spreading that virus to the photo
frames. And those photo frames were then
being delivered. They'd go to our houses
and then on our networks once it got on
the network it was spreading within our
homes across that into some of the
computers on our network. And so that
attacker by spreading and hitting that
production target, he was able to then
spread his virus out to a whole bunch of
homes and other networks, targets he may
not have otherwise had access to. So
that's kind of an idea of what can
happen in that threat model. Now imagine
that he's not targeting photo frames for
grandma. Imagine that now he's targeting
controllers for an F-35 jet, right? And
he wants to put some malicious software
on that. If he can get to the test
system that is testing an F-35 or is
testing the 747 or if he can get on to
the station that's testing your cell
phones, I mean, that's a pretty good
target for him to get to so that he can
drive his malicious code out to many,
many different devices and critical
devices. So, I think that's kind of the
main one we think about when we think
about test. When we think about, you
know, these programmable controllers
that we can put out there, now you're
talking about a target that may be
controlling a vital asset, right? Like
an electrical grid, water purification
systems, big systems like that. And that
target and that mechanism, the threat
model there is a little bit different,
but still has a pretty juicy target
behind that. So, if I understand
correctly, the OT stuff that we're
talking about, you're kind of dividing
into two groups. There's the test group
and in that case the target is often
whatever you're testing and the other
group is more of like industrial type
control systems or something along those
lines and in there the the actual system
that's being controlled could be the
target. That's right. Okay. And there's
a lot of industrial control out there
and there's so much industrial control
that when government regulators and
security experts think about operational
technology they're primarily thinking
about industrial control systems. My
point here is the other half of OT is
something we don't think about a lot,
but it's the test systems. It's the
testers. And so securing those testers
is a really important thing that we have
to also have threat models and defenses
set up in order to protect that because
we touch so many different devices
coming out of those testers. And I also
imagine that could scale really well as
as well. If you have, for example,
factory producing iPhones, how many
iPhones can they produce in a week or a
month? And exactly. Yeah, that's a lot
of targets. Yeah. And some of them are
pretty smart devices, right? So, you
know, a valve turns on and off and you
can do some things, but some of these
devices, you know, most devices are
consumer products that are made have
some kind of a controller inside of it.
And so, if they can get to the operating
system, the firmware that's down in
those systems and embed something, they
not only have breadth in what they can
expand to, but there's a lot that those
devices are capable of. And the world is
going more and more in that direction,
right? So, as we expand now more into
this IoT world and your refrigerators,
your toasters, your cars, all of those
things become more connected to each
other, that just opens up the gate now
for more of these attacks to come in and
hit those things. It's interesting you
mentioned firmware because I talked to a
lot of test engineers and part of the
test sometimes is making sure that the
device that they're testing has the
latest firmware. So, they're writing
firmware to the device, in which case if
somehow somebody maliciously injected
something in there, it would get into
the device. Yeah. or a lot of these test
lines, they'll actually put some test
firmware down on the device and then
remove that and then download the final
testware. So yeah, most or not most, but
a lot of test systems have access to the
firmware to write that software down. So
an attack there could be pretty lethal.
Another big challenge with a lot of the
test and measurement systems is that
many of them are programmed using a
language called Lab View and perhaps
another tool called test stand. Do you
want to talk about what those are a
little bit and how they work and some of
the challenges? Yeah, and those are
challenges for us specifically because
those are our products, right? Lab View
is a great engineering tool. It's a
programming language. It's a programming
language that allows you to program
graphically. So, as a programmer, we
often think in terms of flow and how a
program might flow. Like, first I'm
going to collect some data from this
device. So, I'm going to record the
temperature coming off of this device
and then I'm going to evaluate that
temperature and based on that I'm going
to make a decision and then I'm going to
output some signal. And each of those is
kind of a step. Well, in Lab View, you
actually just draw with icons. You draw
that flow out. And so, there's an icon
that acquires the temperature, and
there's an icon that does some kind of
math, and there's an icon that puts that
on a chart, and there's an icon that
evaluates that against some limits. And
it's cool software because for somebody
who doesn't know how to program, you can
just drop that down, and you have access
to all of the programming tools that
programmers have. And, you know, around
the world, there are thousands and
thousands of Lab View developers. And I
personally love Lab View because it's
fun to program in, but I also get to do
things that I I don't really have to
have a degree in to be able to do. If
you are a good software developer and
you have good software engineering
skills, you can bring those into the
Laview world and you can really leverage
those. So, for example, the fact that
it's graphical means that in one picture
you can draw two different loops that
are operating at different speeds. And
so now you've got a multi-threaded
application without doing any kind of
thread handling. And all of that happens
naturally inside of Lab View. And you
can just have these different loops
doing different things at the same time.
So it's it's a pretty fun world to be
able to do this stuff in Lab View. Lab
View though does present unique
challenges for security because the
industry has developed a lot of standard
tools around textbased languages to
evaluate the security of a textbased
language. Right? So if I write an
application in Python or in C++, there's
a lot of tools that I can use to go and
scan my code. When I write a code in Lab
View, it's graphical and I don't really
have access to those same tools. And so
the approach that you take for
evaluating your Lab View code is a
little bit different than in other
textbased languages because we just
don't fit into that broader ecosystem of
textbased languages. Now the other thing
you mentioned was testand. Testand is a
sequencing engine. So, if you think
about when you run a test, let's say
you're going to test a printer, you're
going to run through and test maybe a
hundred different functions of that
printer to make sure that they all work
right. So, you're going to rotate one of
the wheels and make sure that it turned
the correct amount. You're going to look
at the torque on that wheel and make
sure that that wasn't out of line or
whatever. So, you're going to run about
maybe 100 maybe a thousand tests. And as
a programmer, when I write my tests, I
have to think about writing the
individual step and how I'm going to
access the real world, right? How do I
record the torque on that wheel? How do
I record the amount of turns that it
turned when I told it to turn? How do I
record the voltage going into the wheel
motor? That kind of thing. That's the
step function. But then there's also how
do I pass data from one step to the
next? And how do I put that into the
report? How do I manage the user that is
logged into everything? And that's what
we would call the test executive
functions, right? So it's managing those
steps that you write. Testand is written
to do all of that for you and allow you
to write those steps in any language
that you want and you can mix and match
those. So if you have a team of
developers, some of them use Python,
some of them use C C#, some of them use
Lab View, they could each write their
code and combine those back together and
then the executive function. So stepping
from step to step and writing the
report, all that stuff is done for you
inside of test stand and testing testand
for security. The challenge there is
that most testers, most security experts
don't really understand that
differentiation between running an
actual step and a sequencer. So when
they want to look at like where's the
code? Well, testand's not code. Testand
holds code. So how do you test the
container? And again, that's not a real
mature security market. So we've had to
kind of develop our own approaches to
those and then work with security
experts to train them to say, "Hey, this
is what you're looking for and this is
how well it works." and just kind of
work with them to make that happen. So
if I understand correctly then test is
kind of like a meta language. So I would
then test and I define these are the
test steps that I want to run and this
is the order and maybe these repeat each
other and these loop around and these go
in the database and these don't. I
define all that at the test stand but
then the individual steps are all small
chunks of code that reach out to the
real world. That's right. So you can
execute and write those small snippets
of code really quickly without worrying
about how it's going to fit into the
overall piece. How am I going to
sequence you? Like you said, looping
around because sometimes you want to hit
a step and then loop several times
before you jump out of that loop and go
to the next step. And sometimes you want
to loop until it fails a certain number
of times. So all of that logic is what
I'm calling the test executive
functions. And yeah, Testan does all of
that separate from the individual codes.
What that means, you have to think about
your security at a couple different
levels. You have to think about the
security of my code, you know, right?
What I've written in C++ and the
components that I've used to make that
step work versus the test end
environment and how it's sequencing
through and whether or not anything is
exposed there to any malicious actors.
So, you've kind of got two security
fronts to work on. Yeah. You mentioned
analysis tools for security that exist
for other programming languages. One
I've heard a lot of is I think it's SAS
versus DAS which is like dynamic versus
static code checking. What does Lab View
and or Testand offer in those areas?
You're right. So there there are two a
couple ways to look at the testing your
code right. Stass or SAS or DAS or just
static and dynamic. And in the dynamic
world, it's not much different testing
Lav view code versus any other kind of
code because in the dynamic world,
you're looking at as it's running, what
does it look like and what's open, how
is it using and swapping its memory and
doing all that kind of stuff. And the
way that Lab View does that is the same
that anybody else does anything in any
language, right? So it all gets compiled
down to assembly and it does its thing.
So the tools that look at the dynamic
testing are really no different from Lab
View than they are anywhere else. So
that part's easy. The hard part is in
the static testing because it is this
graphical language. So when people come
in and they want to do the static
analysis, they're asking how do I scan
my code and look for malicious code or
or bad code. And the problem with that
is that static testing is so huge. It's
a huge vast field, right? So if I were
to come and ask you to go and look at
your code that you've written in C and
you will tell me that there's no
security vulnerabilities in it, how
would you do that? Right? You might
start by looking to see did I make any
calls that are known to do bad things?
Did I make any calls that allow me to
overwrite memory? But attackers know so
many different ways to attack our code.
So we have to be thinking about how am I
going to protect against all those
different things. So security protection
in something like C++ or C# is a wide
open field. You have to just account for
every possible way that somebody can
attack you. And that's what these large
static analysis tools do is they've got
experts that sit around and think all
the time about how would I find the ways
that people attack code. So for example,
we know that one of the common ways that
people attack code is that they will
issue a database command into like a
password field or something and it will
take that field back when it's supposed
to take it to the database and instead
of taking it to the database, it will
execute that function. So the way that
you block that is that you verify any of
the commands that you send into your
database to make sure that it's sending
what you think it's sending. Like if
it's supposed to send a username, you
only send the username and you strip off
any other database commands from that.
So that's something that a static tool
will go and look for, but malicious
actors are coming up with new attacks
all the time. So people have to
continually be updating those static
analysis tools to keep looking for those
things. In the Lab View world, there's a
couple of things that make that a little
bit harder. One is we don't have the
huge user base that you have. You know,
we've got thousands or tens of thousands
of users of Lab View, but we don't have
the millions of users that you have with
Python or C. So we don't have the volume
of people that are looking at this
problem and creating these mature tools
that can do everything right. So that
just makes that naturally harder and
also the fact that we are a graphical
language makes that harder. So we have
to create scanning tools and we do have
scanning tools but we make those
scanning tools and we allow you to
program those scanning tools go look for
things inside of Lab View. Designing
that to go look for every possible
attack that the other people are looking
for in the textbased tools. It's a huge
undertaking, a huge task, and we haven't
been able to do that fully to this
point. So, we're behind them on that,
which means that if I'm a Lavview
developer, I am probably going to have
to do some manual checks, right? So, I'm
going to manually have to think, is
there a place in my code where I'm
calling a database? And have I done
anything there that would expose the
database call to something that the user
enters or am I blocking that? And so,
we've created some of those kinds of
guides to say, here's the top security
things to look for. And if you are
creating some LAV view code, then you
need to look at whether or not you've
implemented these things correctly. We
have some automated tools that can help
with that. But it's going to be a
combination of at this point of doing
some of the automated work mixed with
some manual review to make sure that
your code is secure. Yeah, I was going
to say in my experience, that's what
it's been is them automatic review flags
certain things and then you have to go
and and double check them. Yeah. And you
know, to be safe, we probably would have
to over flag things and say, "Hey,
you're making a database call here. did
you do it right? And over here you're
calling the command line and what are
you doing that for? And so just checking
and and having you flag that as a
developer to say yes, I know what I'm
doing here and I'm controlling for the
inputs to that. Both of us have been
working in the test and measurement
industry for several decades. What
changes have you seen over that time in
terms of security, particularly people's
attitudes towards security and maybe
some major attacks or regulations or
things that have happened over the past
decade or two? Yeah, you know, that's a
great question because things have
changed a lot for us, right, over the
years. If I think back to when I
started, which was back in the 90s,
people were really more concerned about
just getting data into my computer. And
then over the next 10 years, there was
more of an effort to say, how do I use
that data than other I got this in my
computer? Right? So, if I'm producing a
part of a car over time, I wanted to
look at not just did this unit pass or
fail, but let's look at how many of my
units are passing and failing and why
are units on this line passing more
often than units on that line. So how to
can I become more efficient? And that
required that we started to network our
test stations together so that we could
see and share and use that data. And now
in the last year or the last few months,
it's become a lot more important to say,
hey, how can I take all of my data and
pull all of that together so that I can
start running AI on that to have AI
identify some trends and things that are
happening inside my test station. That's
really interesting to be able to do all
that, but it does require that you
network all of those stations together.
When we started to see engineers putting
things together to create these worked
systems and sharing data among their
systems, we started to see this conflict
or at least this friction arise between
the test teams and the IT teams. So the
IT guys always controlled the networks.
They always controlled all the computer
stuff. And now these test guys were
bringing in these new systems. And these
new systems were now going to connect to
each other and do things. And when the
test team came to the IT team and said,
"We're going to drop stuff on your
network." The IT guys said, "Hey, no, we
we don't even understand what that stuff
is. Don't put that on my network." So
the test teams set up their own
networks. And those networks really
didn't need to have any kind of
connection to the outside world. So they
created a network, but they, as they
called it, airgapped that from the rest
of the network. So they had their own
little network, just an intranet. they
could share data among those different
devices, but they didn't really care
about security because they weren't
connected to the real world. And there
was no reason to really worry about it
because we just weren't talking about
security generally for these test
systems. And as time has gone on, two
things have happened. Number one, those
isolated networks have now needed to
become not isolated anymore. as you
implement AI tools and you need to
connect to these models and do all all
kinds of other stuff and you want to
report your data out. they now do need
to connect to the corporate network to
share that data in and out and that
creates that surface where you can
attack through and now the IT guys say
hey wait if you're going to put this on
my network security becomes really
important now then the other thing that
we've seen happen is that over the years
we've seen attacks on those airgap
networks so even though we hoped that
nobody would ever figure out how to
attack an airgapped system people have
figured out how to do that and I think
the most famous example of that is the
stuckset thing that happened over in
Iran where they were processing uranium
and these gyroscopes were controlled by
PLC's and those PLC's were attacked and
a virus got to those PLC's that made the
results of those gyros off a little bit
and that delayed their uranium and in
this case we might be rooting for that
with Iran and getting nuclear weapons
and all that kind of stuff but the thing
that was really important to notice
about that is that those systems that
they had inside that factory were
airgapped
and they were able to get the virus
spread among those by walking in with a
USB stick and somehow getting that USB
stick plugged into that intranet that
even though it was airgapped now was
sharing that virus among its different
units. So if you go today as we were
looking at those units and we're saying
hey I have an air gap system is probably
safe. Well we know that it's probably
not safe there's other ways to get to
that air gap network that could affect
that. And we've seen that with a number
of other systems over the years too
where we've seen some of the gas pipes
and some of the other attacks that have
happened. Several of those have happened
on systems that we thought were safe
because they were airgapped. So over the
last, I'd say three years, we've seen a
really big push from the IT and security
teams to go back to the test teams and
say, "Hey, that system that you have
that is airgapped, it still needs to
comply with all these security
requirements, and we still need to make
sure that it's locked down, and we still
need to make sure that it's going to
keep us safe." And that has put these
test teams kind of in a defensive
position to figure out how do we update
our systems so that we've got zero trust
so that we've got controls at the
boundaries. We've got controls inside of
these to make sure that any attacks are
going to be protected and defended. That
brings up another question I hadn't
thought of until now. How do you deal
with aging control systems? Because I
imagine some of these systems have been
around for 15 or 20 years and are
probably still running really old
operating systems and things like that.
How do you handle that? Not very well is
is honestly the answer. If you look at
the way that many of these test projects
have been funded, this is true from
making little toys for little kids all
the way up to big Department of Defense
projects. The way that they get funded
is that when you have a project and
you're going to make a new car, like
we're going to make this version of this
car, the company funds that project and
they fund the test system as part of
that project. and they really don't like
to put any money in for continuous
maintenance and continuous upgrades on
that system. So, they kind of like to
just lock it and leave it right where
it's at. And that's true on cars where
that lifetime might be 5 years, 10
years, but it's also true on airplanes
and military airplanes where the
lifetime is 20, 30, or 40 years. And so
we have had customers come to us and
say,"I want to buy your equipment, but I
want you to tell me that this exact
build of hardware and this exact build
of software are going to be available to
me for the next 20 years." And that's
really difficult to do for all kinds of
different reasons. But now with this new
emphasis on security, it's not only hard
to do, it's a bad idea to do because one
of the top priorities in doing security
is continuous upgrades. You've got to
keep your system up to date. And if
you're not keeping your system up to
date, then you are falling behind and
malicious actors can go and attack you
with old technologies or attack your old
technologies with new and innovative
ways to get around that. So, it's a real
challenge in the test industry because
we don't get the funding that we need to
do continuous maintenance. But, we've
got to figure out how to do it because
if we don't, then these systems and
again the military systems are some of
the most critical systems. they fall
farther and farther behind and become
more and more exploitable by malicious
actors. It's not something that's been
figured out in the industry so far.
Currently, a lot of regulations seem to
apply to government purchases and
military expenses and things that are
export controlled. What effect do you
see these regulations having on regular
commercial products? Yeah, that's a good
question because in the US, we seem to
be hesitant to try to regulate
commercial products. There's a little
bit of oversight. You can get a UL
stamp, but it's not really required on
anything. Maybe there's some industries
where that's not true, but the US
doesn't roll out broad regulations for
commercial products when it comes to
security. So, the US government can
control that in the way that they buy.
So, they can roll out with any of the
government contracts. They can say if
you're going to sell this to the
government, it has to meet these
security requirements. It has to be safe
in this way, has to be safe in that way,
etc., etc. And so we have seen over the
last couple years new regulations come
in from the US government that apply to
US government purchases. And so the big
one is coming through the Department of
Defense and that is this program called
the cyber security maturity model
certification or CMMC. And CMMC says
that if you're going to sell to the
government or you're going to
communicate with the government even
your products have to meet these
requirements. And there's 110
requirements that are laid out in a
document from NIST called NIST
800-171. And if I'm going to handle
government data as part of my
transaction with the government, I have
to show that I can protect that data to
all 110 of those requirements, including
my production line, right? So my
production line, if I'm producing like a
I don't know, ignition for a F-35 jet or
something, I have to show that the test
system is going to meet all of those
requirements so that it's not going to
be attacked and end up in you know the
results we talked about earlier. But the
government only can really roll that out
through the government contracting
system, which means if you're selling
something to the government and the
biggest part of the government that buys
stuff is the Department of Defense. So
that's kind of leading the charge when
it comes to that. in the US for
commercial things. I haven't really seen
much of a protection there. There's a
little bit that maybe gets rolled into
medical devices, but those are more
quality initiatives, less so security.
Trying to think if I've seen other
things. So, they're kind of up to the
companies. And so, some of our customers
who are I've seen it from some of the
automotive manufacturers, I've seen it
from some of the electronics
manufacturers. They come to us and they
say, "If you're going to sell to us,
your products need to meet a certain
standard of security." But there's not a
broad regulation that requires that.
Now, if we switch, we can talk about
Europe and that's a little bit
different. But I want to pause there and
see if you have any questions about the
US system first. No, that all makes
sense to me. So, let's go ahead and talk
about Europe. So, Europe is taking a
different stance and they are a little
more controlling when it comes to like
commercial devices. And they have used
pretty effectively for I don't know how
many years now the CE stamp, right? So,
if you're going to sell something into
Europe, you've got to have a CE stamp
that shows that you meet a certain level
of quality, which will include some of
the materials that you use, the
emissions that come out of it, the
electronic radiation that comes out of
it, those kinds of things. So, if I'm
going to sell into Europe, I'm going to
get that C mark. And we're all used to
that. And if you turn over most of your
electronics, you'll see a a CE mark on
the back of it that shows this product
can be sold to the US, but it could also
be sold to Europe. Now, Europe in 2023
rolled out a new regulation that was
finalized in 2024, takes effect at the
beginning of 2025, and then we have two
almost 3 years to enact all of the
things that are in that regulation. And
the regulation from Europe is called the
European Cyber Security Resilience Act
or we call it the CRA for short. That
CRA says if you're going to sell any
kind of digital product is how they
determine it and a digital product is
anything that connects to something else
and has a digital interface. So if it
runs software if you're going to sell a
digital product into Europe it's going
to have to get a new C mark and that new
CE mark has behind it a bunch of cyber
security regulations. So those include
things like developing the product with
a secure development framework in mind.
It includes basic cyber hygiene like
having default passwords on devices like
a network router, those kinds of things.
And it includes that if you sell
software, you know, the firmware that's
on a device into Europe, it has to be
delivered with no known exploitable
vulnerabilities. And so, you know, as as
software goes along, say Log 4j came out
a couple years ago as like this
component that was affecting a lot of
us. The European regulation says that if
you've got log 4j in your device, you
can't sell the device into Europe.
You've got to remove that and make sure
that it's not in there and you've got to
have a full analysis done before you can
do that. So this new C marks shipping
things into Europe is going to force
lots and lots of us to really have a
good cyber hygiene in our development
systems, in our test systems, and in the
devices that we make so we can continue
to ship those into Europe. the full ban
on that comes into play at the end of
2027.
So now I'd like to pivot a little bit
and I'd like to do a deep dive on a
particular product that NI sells called
a C RIO. Can you tell me a little bit
about what a C RIO is? Yeah, C Rio or
the full name is compact RIO. So I'm
kind of flipped back and forth probably
in the name, but a compact RIO device is
cool. It's an input output device.
That's kind of how it started. And it's
a rugged input output device. It's a
modular system. So imagine an eight slot
chassis about the size of a I don't know
a football maybe. Yeah. So you got a
chassis that big that has either four or
eight slots in it. And these modules you
can put in that each module will give
you an interface to a different kind of
sensor. So we've got a thermouple
sensor. We've got a microphone sensor.
So you can you can acquire data from
accelerometers or microphones. There's
digital lines. There's high voltage and
low voltage lines. And so as I said
earlier where we interface to the real
world, these are the modules you
interface to the real world with. That's
what you connect those sensors into is
these different modules. And the first
version of this which we call compact
DAC connects those modules back through
Ethernet or USB back to your computer.
And then your computer tells it what to
do. It tells it to acquire the data and
then it makes the decisions. Well, we
took a real time processor and we've
used a couple different variations, but
we're using Intel chips right now. And
we push that Intel chip down into that
chassis itself and it runs a real-time
operating system. So you can write your
code, push it down into that and have it
run locally, disconnect the cable and
and leave it doing whatever it's going
to do out there and and kind of run its
own thing. So you can kind of think
about it as like uh Raspberry Pi except
that it's got way more capability
because you can plug in these different
modules and it's running a much more
powerful processor than that. But it is
running a Linux operating system. But
that Linux operating system, it's based
on a real-time kernel of Linux and so it
gives us real-time performance. So that
gives us determinism and very low jitter
and high reliability. So you can trust
that system to run really well. So
that's one of the cool things we do with
Compact Rio. And then the other cool
thing we do with Compact Rio is we push
an FPGA chip down there and you can
program that FPGA chip. So we should
talk about that FPGA chip too, but let
me pause and see if you have a comment
or question about that. Yeah. No, I
wanted to talk about both parts. I think
let's talk about the RT Linux first. So
this is a very specific distribution of
Linux that NI maintains. That's right.
It's an open source. We have the
distribution on GitHub, but it really
only runs on the NI platforms because
it's pretty tied into the actual
hardware that's there. We've got a lot
of magic that's in the back plane of
these chassis that include timing chips
and other things. And so it's pretty
specific to that platform. So I can plug
in these different modules and then I've
got this real-time operating system. If
you log into it, it looks and feels like
Linux because it is a version of L
Linux, but it is a real-time version.
So, it's missing some of the bells and
whistles and user interface things. It's
missing that in order to maintain that
high level of determinism that we need
to get for a real time controller that
we put down there. So, NI maintains that
distribution. We put that on GitHub.
Right now, we are running off of Linux 6
point. We're about to release a 6 point
of one based on Linux 6.6 and we'll
start working on kind of an update to
that kernel that will come out again in
another year. So we continue to upgrade
those to take advantage of features but
also to remove some of the
vulnerabilities that pop up in the
stack. What is different about securing
an RT Linux installation as opposed to
just a regular Linux desktop or server?
A lot of it's the same. In fact, we are
able to leverage a lot of the same
tools. So you know I have customers that
call me and ask me just today a customer
asked me how do I store certificates in
your Linux realtime system? And the
answer to that we found by looking at
the way that Red Hat Linux does their
certificate storage because it's just
standard Linux stuff. It's a certificate
distribution something. Anyway, we found
that solution for that, tested it on our
solution and it works the same. So, a
lot of it works exactly the same. Where
it's different is that we've had to
optimize the NI Linux somewhat to meet
our own model, what our customers are
trying to do. And specifically one of
the things we try to do is we make it
possible to program this target using
Lab View. So I can program using my
graphical icons. I can program this
thing and then I can download my code.
And we tried to really simplify that
experience for our customers so that
they can develop their code and deploy
it without really doing a lot of extra
work. And that makes it highly usable
but it it does make it more vulnerable
overall because the users have to be
able to they don't have to log in to get
into that system. So making a compact
RIO system secure means that you have to
go in and disable some of the things
that we've turned on to optimize ease of
use and you have to disable those things
to optimize the security of the system.
And so we've actually had to spend time
over the last couple of years
documenting exactly all the ways that
you can convert one of these compact Rio
systems from its standard optimized for
use case. and we created it's about 30
or 40 steps of things that you turn on
and that you turn off in order to
optimize it for security, but it's
Linux. So, the cool thing about that is
it's really easy to to write a script
that runs through and does all that for
you. So, we've created a script we
posted on our GitHub repository that
will go through and basically convert
your compact reel from optimized for use
to optimized for security. And it
changes your interaction with it a bit,
but it does make it secure. So, if I
understand correctly, there would be a
development environment mode or settings
or configuration where it's easy to
develop with and it's easy to move files
back and forth and do all the stuff you
need to do and then when you go to
deploy it, you would lock it down before
you shift it off somewhere. Yeah. One of
the ways that you can see what's
happening on it is we have a little web
server that runs there and reports to
you through a graphical interface what's
running, how it's running, and all that
stuff. and when you go to deploy it, you
need to turn that off because the way
that we get into that is through a web
server that's not as secure as it needs
to be. So, we turn all of that off when
we go to deploy it and that makes it
secure. We have customers using these
devices in some very secure areas and
doing some pretty cool stuff with it.
But, we do help those customers make
those secure so they can't be attacked.
Speaking of security, you mentioned
updates to Nir. How do you get updates
to the CBOS? Do they have like a package
manager or something? So, you know,
there's a couple ways cuz the thing with
our compact Rio and the NI Linux real
world is we have two types of customers,
two customer bases. There's ones that
are Linux people that are looking for a
highly powerful, highly capable system.
And those guys, they know too much for
their own good and they like to get it
and they like to really do stuff. And
then there's my customers that come from
the Windows world and their programming
and this is just a device that we've
told them that they can download their
lab view u code to and they don't even
want to know that it's Linux down there.
They don't want to know any of that
magic that's down there. They just want
it to be magic. And so we have to figure
out how to cater to both of those
groups. And so if we have a a script
that they can just run and update things
with and you can log in and we say go
log in as root and do all this stuff.
Half of my customers will do that and
they'll love it. But the other half of
my customers, they'll have no idea what
I'm talking about. They haven't seen a
textbased prompt on an OS since Windows
3.1, right? So that's kind of confusing
to them. And so they don't want to deal
with it that way. But the other ones,
the ones that use my package manager,
they'll deploy that and they'll update
their system like it's a connected
device and they're just right clicking
and updating the firmware. And that's
how they want it to feel and they won't
really know how it's happening. For some
of my Linux guys, that drives them crazy
not knowing what's going on down there.
And so both parties have to cater to
both of those. And so yeah, we have both
ways. You can go to GitHub and you can
download a package and you can update
that and you can make all the command
calls you need to make to update the
system or you can update it from Windows
with a couple of right clicks on a
graphical interface. So while we're
speaking of package managers, there's a
package manager that runs on the CRIO
that handles like the Linux updates, but
there's also two other package managers
involved in the Lab View ecosystem as
well. Correct. Yeah. So there's yeah
there's a couple different package
managers and a couple different things
you have to keep updated because we're
talking here about the LAV software.
We're talking about the NI Linux
real-time OS software. There's also some
drivers mixed in there. And so balancing
all of that means you have to become an
expert in the workflow for our products.
And again, that workflow varies based on
if you're coming to us from the Linux
world or if you're coming to us from the
Lab View world. But we have to try to
support those different things. I
honestly don't even remember off the top
of my head the names of all the
different package managers, but yeah,
there are a couple different ones in
there to help you out. I know a big
topic in cyber security in general
recently has been package managers and
supply chain security. Has there been
any instances of any of that in the NI
ecosystem? How does NI work to prevent
that? I have a lot of customers worried
about that. Fortunately, I have not had
any customers come to me with an actual
case where they've said, "This has
happened. I don't have any cool stories
to tell you and I'm glad that I don't
have any cool stories to tell you that
about that. So customers come in and the
whole supply chain because supply chain
is a topic of several of the
requirements in this NIST 800-171 and
that applies to both software and
hardware. So how do you ensure like if a
company comes to me and they buy my
software and they download it from the
web, how do they ensure that what they
received from us over the web is what we
intended for them to receive. So they'll
ask me several questions. So they'll ask
me during your build process, how do you
protect the code so that your final
product that gets built is what you
think you were building? And then once
you have those bits done and you go to
put those on the web, how do you verify
that those bits made it to the web and
that nobody else interfered with that
and put the wrong bits on the web? And
then when I download those bits from
you, how do I verify that what I
received is what you posted there for me
to receive? And the way that we do all
of that is through hashes and check
sums. So we're constantly creating and
and as we make handoffs from one place
to the next and especially when we put
that on the web, we put two different
hashes, two different check sums that
are done two different ways. So when my
customer downloads those installers,
they can verify those check sums to make
sure that what they downloaded is what
we had intended for them to download in
the first place. And it's really hard
for a malicious actor to spoof that
check sum to make that pass. And to
spoof two different ones is is
impossible. So that's how we do that. Is
that a manual check or does that get
automatically happen at some points?
It's a manual check, but there are
automated tools that help you to do
that. So that kind of gets into the next
thing, which is now my customer now that
he's downloaded the code, how does he
verify that nothing has changed on his
system after he's downloaded and
installed it, right? Because I could set
it up and run and have my code and every
day come in and start up that computer,
start up the code, and run it on my
production line. But a malicious actor
could come in and swap out one of the
DLS in the middle of the night. And how
would I know that he did that? And so
there are file checking mechanisms for
doing that that just kind of run
automated that you can point it to a
folder and say, "Hey, run this and you
should see this check sum every day or
every time you run." And if that
checksum ever changes, it means that
somebody changed that file. Now, you
don't want to do that if it's a data
file that you're writing to because then
you'll constantly be alarmed by that.
But for static files that should never
change, it's a good idea to put this
file checking in place so that you're
constantly checking that check sum and
make sure that that file doesn't get
changed. Do these cos have any kind of
secure boot technology to make sure that
like whatever kernel boots is what and I
intended. Yeah. So as we boot up, we
will do some kind of a check some. We're
actually that's a a thing that we're
improving right now because we haven't
had a TPM chip on the the compact in the
past. And so maybe we need to stop and
talk about what a TPM chip is good for
real quick. Yeah, just real quick. TPM
is trusted platform module. What TPM
chips let you do, the simplest way to
think about it is that they are a
storage place for secret information
like passwords and stuff. So, if I have
code that I'm going to run on startup,
if I can take a check sum from that code
and check that to make sure that it's
correct, that's going to make sure I'm
running the right code. Well, where are
you going to store that key to check
against? The best place to put that is
in a TPM chip in hardware that's locked
down. And that's the whole point of a
TPM chip is that it's really difficult
to change those keys. So when I start
up, I can check and say this software
that's running, does it check against my
TPM and the key that's stored inside my
TPM? If it is, great. Everybody's happy.
So you can use TPMs in a lot of
different ways, right? Windows uses TPM
on boot up just to check and make sure
that your hard drive didn't get swapped
out and that everybody is the right hard
drive. But you can access those as a
user. There's lots of programs that
allow you to access those TPMs and to
store other kinds of information. So you
can store your keys, you can store web
certificates, whatever you want to store
there. you can do that and so we're
adding those. We have a a version of our
compact rio now that has a TPM chip so
customers can do that check against
their software but right now it's a
little bit more manual and we're working
through to make that more automated.
Great. We have about 10 more minutes. I
got two more topics I want to talk
about. So all right the first one you
had mentioned earlier is FPGA. What does
that stand for and what is an FPGA?
Yeah. So this is kind of a cool
technology but if you look at what it
takes to make an integrated chip, right?
An integrated chip is what you if you
open up your your laptop and you look at
all those chips in there, you have all
these chips that have digital logic
inside of them. And the problem with an
integrated chip is that to make one, it
costs a million dollars and it takes a
long time to create everything. You have
to send it off to some fab like say it
literally cost can cost like a million
dollars to create a new chip. And so an
FPGA is what's called a field
programmable gate array. And the
important part of it is those first two
letters. It's a field programmable,
which means it's an integrated chip, but
instead of being fixed in its
personality, it's full of a bunch of
hardware gates and you can program those
gates to take on any digital personality
that you want to download to it. So, I
can program it and then use that in
devices. And we see those in a lot of
like lower volume devices. So, if you're
not going to make a million of a device,
it doesn't really make sense to go and
create custom IC's for that. Instead,
you can buy these FPGAAS and program
those FPGAs. We don't make FPGAs, but
you go to companies like XYlinks and
they make those FPGAAS. But what we've
done that's innovative is that we
created some hardware because again our
our whole goal is to interface to the
real world. We made some hardware that
has these FPGAAS on it behind some of
our analog circuitry so that you can
program that FPGA to do whatever you
would program the board to do so that it
can make decisions and do things that a
chip would do without even involving
your CPU and your computer. And so we
have a few different products that use
those FPGAAS. And we have a version of
Lab View that lets you graphically
program that FPGA. So most programming
for those FPGA, if you're programming
for XYlinks or the other companies,
you're programming with HDL. I don't
even know what HDL stands for anymore,
but it's a programming language that's
targeted at FPGAAS. And that's a kind of
a a highly unique programming style. I'm
sure some of your listeners are HDL
programmers, but with Laview, you can
program and we will compile that down
into the HDL code and download it to the
FPGA chip. And we put one of those chips
on that compact RIO device. So now that
compact Rio device has really three
elements to it. It has the modules, it
has the real-time processor and it's got
a programmable FPGA chip on it and we
expose that to you as a user. So now
when I'm architecting my application, I
can decide what functions do I want to
have running on the real-time operating
system and with that I'll get
performance where I can run loops that
are like 10 microsconds or maybe a
couple of microsconds. If I'm
controlling a valve or something, that's
plenty speed. But I can also use that
FPGA. And in that FPGA, I can download
and I can run things at hardware speeds
where I can do things much much faster.
So I can do inline processing of some of
the signals or I can count things. I can
control loops. Now if I do a control
loop on the FPGA, I can close that
control loop in somewhere around 5 or 10
nanconds as opposed to 5 or 10
microsconds. So I can go many times
faster than I can with the processor.
And both of those will go a lot faster
than what I can do with a Windows
processor on a Windows computer. So it
gets into where I can now architect
things really really well. But you know
the interesting thing about FPGAAS is
people don't really understand them,
especially security people. And so I've
had some of my customers, their security
teams have come to them and said, "I
have a notice here from the NSA that
says you cannot use FPGAs because
they're not secure." And we have to stop
and say, "Hold on. What What do you mean
by this not secure?" when you turn power
off to an FPGA, all the gates open and
it's clear and it's open. And you can
write things to the FPGA if you feel
like you need to to kind of mess it up
to do things. And we have those kinds of
routines to help clear an FPGA. So,
we've met with customers to try to
explain to them how an FPGA works to
their security teams and then explain to
them how to clear that. And then we also
work with our test teams to explain to
them how to use that chip securely. So,
if you think about some of the concepts
we've talked about in the last 15
minutes, the most secure way to use an
FPGA, at least the way that we've
architected ours, is to leave the FPGA
open and when you boot up from the drive
on the real-time system, check that the
FPGA bit file has not changed on disk
and then download that bit file to the
FPGA so that the FPGA is now running
code that you know is the code that you
downloaded and nobody can come in and
play with that and change that code.
Another question that popped into my
mind. You mentioned that the lab view
code gets compiled down into VHDL. Does
that make it easier to do some static
analysis on the VHDL code? Are there any
tools for that or does that not really
exist? There are even on Lab View for
Windows and on the realtime side, we
compile the code down into assembly. So
you've got a bunch of bits. And so
there's code that runs looking at the
textbased code that's looking at like
the words that you and I speak, right?
It's looking for the if and then and and
the the other programming commands, but
there are static analysis tools that
look at the binary files and they try to
look for is there something there and
that way they can find things that are
deeply buried inside the code. The
problem with that is it seems to miss a
lot and you get a lot of false
positives. And so customers that run
against the binaries, they'll contact us
and say, "Hey, we ran against your
binary and we think we found this thing
because it had some detectable pattern."
And when we look into it, sometimes it's
right. Sometimes it's like they found
something that does not exist and we
have to kind of work with them on that.
You know, it's got some kind of a match,
but it's not a really good match. And
then we look at the report and and go,
we know that there are other things in
there that they should have seen that
they didn't see. The binary check is
it's an okay way. It's maybe like a
third way to kind of look at things.
It's not a guaranteed way to make sure
that your code is not running any
vulnerable components. I have one last
topic I want to hit on and I think this
is a good one because it does help to
differentiate IT versus OT. A lot of OT
devices are connected to industrial
communications networks. Can you talk a
little bit about what those are? What
makes them different from regular
networks and maybe some of the
challenges of trying to secure those?
Yeah, when I think about industrial
networks, I think about communication
protocols like Modbus or CAN or Proyet,
Profy bus. There's a lot of different
ones that have different advantages
based on what you're trying to do. So,
some of them are used in wastewater
treatment plants. Some of them are used
in power grids. Some of them have faster
or slower response times. Some of them
can handle more or less data than other
ones. And in a way they can be more
secure than other network devices
because people don't understand like how
do you hack into a modbus network. But
on the other hand, a lot of these
networks over the last 20 years have
migrated away from they were running on
maybe 485 serial buses or other kind of
weirder connections between them.
They've migrated over to be running on
the Ethernet on the TCP IP network. So
Modbus has become mostly now Modbus TCP
IP where it runs on that network. So
what kind of made them different before
has kind of gone away and they're kind
of on that same network and I think I
wouldn't trust that a malicious actor
just doesn't know how to use it as a
good security block, right? So I think
you have to think about how do we how do
we block that. The hard thing about
those is that some of those protocols
were made before security became a
primary concern. And so a lot of them
are made without thinking much about how
do we protect these devices on this
particular network. And so those have
become kind of a secondary thought or
either they haven't layered security
into it or the security feels like it's
kind of layered on top. For example, the
security protocol might be block all of
your ports except for this one where
Modbus is being passed through and
that's not the greatest overall
security. It's what a lot of our
infrastructure around the world is based
on for wastewater treatment and gas and
everything else. And so they have
layered a lot of security on top of that
that I'm not that versed in. But it it
does present a unique challenge because
you have to think about those devices in
their own networks and not as part of
like your Windows and IT infrastructure.
Interesting. A question that popped in
my mind. So you mentioned Modbus TCP. So
Modbus TCP, can that run on the same
network cable that runs my normal TCP IP
traffic? And if I plug in Wireshark,
will I see those packets going right
next to my other packets?
Yes. If you're running a big facility,
then you don't do that, right? You run
dedicated cables for doing that. But if
I have a small facility where I'm just I
want to go and grab the data from that
pump over there and bring it back and it
only speaks Modbus, then yeah, it would
just be on your regular network and you
would see that with your Wire Shark.
Okay. Very interesting. Well, thank you
for joining us today and talking about
security. Yeah, it's fun. Thanks for
inviting me for SE Radio. This is Sam
Tagert. Thanks for joining us.
Thanks for listening to SE Radio, an
educational program brought to you by it
e software magazine. For more about the
podcast, including other episodes, visit
our website at se-radio.net.
To provide feedback, you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter, or
through our Slack channel at
seradio.slack.com. You can also email us
at
[Music]
teamse-radio.net. This and all other
episodes of SE Radio is licensed under
creative common license 2.5. Thanks for
listening.